So today we are going to talk about the
dividend of ICICI Lord General Insurance,
so friends the ex-dividend date in this
is 28th i.e. on 2810
if you have ICICI Lombard
shares then in such a situation you will
get dividend, how much dividend are you going to get
friends, at 55 now at 55
we have to calculate how much dividend are you getting from its face value, the
dividend at 55 is what the company is going to give, we
can see its face value here, so
friends its face value is ₹10, that is
if we calculate at 55 as per ₹10 then it
comes to
55, that is 55, that is the dividend that the
company is going to give us, if we have
ICICI Lord shares in our portfolio on 28th then
what is the market price of the company, the
market price of the company is ₹5575 paise right now let
us see what the portfolio of the company
says, friends the
portfolio of the company says that in the last
one year  In 2018, the company has reached 0 from 1332,
which means the company has shown very good
growth. As of
today, it is standing at the level of 1955. So
friends, it is still on a high note, but if we
want, we can buy it for the dividend,
but it is not beneficial to buy it because
you will get
₹ 2000000 of ₹ 923 crores, which means the company
is a fairly big company and
everyone must have heard the name of ICI Lord. This
company works in the insurance sector. As far as the P ratio of the company is seen,
it is 43.5, whereas the P
ratio of the industry is 2.17. This clearly shows
that the company is currently overvalued.
If we look at the company's ascendant, it
is 16.33, which means that the company gives a
profit of around 16 per annum. The
PV ratio of the company is 7.12 and the
dividend is given by the company very less,
which means the dividend of 56 per annum is on the company.
Friends, if companies are paying less dividends, then
they invest their money
in the research and development of the company, so
somewhere or the other, this
benefits the company in the long term, so you should
not run after dividends and should choose those companies
which
invest good money in research and development.
As far as debt to equity is concerned,
debt to equity
is zero. We have seen the face value, friends, it is
10. Now if we talk about the financials of the company,
then the company is showing
good growth yearly. You can see that
from 1133 crores, the company is making
revenue of 20602 today. If we talk about
its profit, then the company is
giving good profit and this too, yearly the
profit of the company is increasing. From
2020 i.e. the Corona period
till 2024, we can see that the company is continuously
increasing in terms of profit. If
we talk about the net worth, then the net worth of the
company is continuously increasing.
Friends, regarding the holding pattern of the company,  You
can see that from September 24 to September 23, the
company's portfolio, which is the promoters
' portfolio, has decreased a bit, that is,
where it was 51.6 in September 24, the
company's portfolio is left at 48. If we
look at the foreign institutions, then
where the
company's portfolio was 24.75 in September 24, it was
2.37 in September 23. Somewhere the foreign institutions have
also reduced their stock a bit from this.
If we talk about mutual funds, then where the
mutual fund was 14.9 in September 24,
it was 15.4 in September 23, so somewhere the
money that has been withdrawn by the foreign institutions in the mutual funds has been
taken by the mutual funds and the
retail sector, which was at 6.86 earlier
and as of today, it has increased to 11, so
somewhere the people from the retail sector have
accepted the shares of this company. As far as the
company is concerned, the company which  It
works in the insurance sector i.e. in the general insurance sector.
Here you can see friends that the
company is linked to the insurance sector
in every sector like car, bike, travel, health, SME, corporate. The company does insurance.
Apart from this, the
company is also involved in the Pradhan Mantri Fasal Bima Yojana through which a lot of money comes from the government. The
company has 3000 plus branches
and you can see the company's chat board, so
somewhere the
company spends well on its research and development
and the company is making
itself boom up, so the company
can be considered a good company. See
friends,
in this, a good amount of funds
come to the company from the government.
As far as we talk about the payer comparison of the company,
friends, then in front of the life insurance of the company,
SBI Life, HDFC General Insurance,
New India Insurance,
you can see what is the condition of ICICI Lord.
So friends, if we
look at the market price, the highest market
price is of ICICI Lord, that is
1955 75 paise, in comparison to that, if we take the top
company, that is, if we take LIC,
which has the highest market capital,
its market price is 912. Apart from this,
you can see
198 and 359 of ADFC Life, we can see
714, so that means the market cap, the
market price
of AC Lombard is the highest. If we
look at the market capitalization, then
LIC is at the top in market capitalization.
Talking about the balance sheet of the company, the
reserve of the company was 9953 in March 2023,
if we look at the same, it was 35 crores, whereas
if we look at the same in September, the
company has reduced it to zero and the
reserve is increasing, this shows that the
company can easily
eliminate its loans and generate profit.